# **MUHAMMAD ABUSAA**

# PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

+10 years experience of software development . Well-versed in technology to create systems that are reliable and user-friendly. Skilled leader who has the proven ability to motivate, educate, and manage a team of professionals to build software programs and effectively track changes. Confident communicator and strategic thinker.

#### **WORK HISTORY**

# TECH TEAM LEAD (CLOUD NATIVE APPLICATIONS), THIQAH BUSINESS SERVICES



1/9/2019 - Present

### PRODUCT MANAGER / TEAM LEAD, NETWAYS, RIYADH



1/1/2018 - 1/8/2019

#### **TECHNICAL TEAM LEADER, NETWAYS, RIYADH**



1/1/2017 - 30/12/2017

#### SENIOR SOLUTION DESIGNER, NETWAYS, RIYADH



1/12/2012 – 1/1/2017

#### SOFTWARE ENGINEER, OGER SYSTEMS, RIYADH



• 1/1/2010 – 30/11/2012

#### **SKILLS**

- Azure DevOps.
- Containerization and Docker.
- Containers orchestration / Kubernetes.
- Kubernetes management and monitoring: Rancher / Prometheus / Grafana.
- Team management / leadership
- .NET Core / Framework.
- Client Side Development
- SharePoint Understanding
- Office 365 Understanding

- CRM Understanding
- BizTalk Understanding
- K2 Understanding
- Angular
- Project Scoping
- Application design
- Preparing demos and related presentation
- Product owner / scrum master / solution management
- System / Business analysis

# PROFESSIONAL ACHIEVEMENTS

#### INTERNET AND ESERVICES PROJECTS

- Amaaly: .NET Core / Docker / Kubernetes.
- Ministry of commerce / Franchise : .NET Core / Angular
- Ministry of commerce / Maroof : .NET Core / Docker and Kubernetes .
- SFDA eservices project : .Net Core , Kubernetes , React
- Ministry of interior Mifon Project : Angular JS , Web Api , SharePoint , CRM
- GMCO internet website : SharePoint 2013 , Word Automation
- The centennial fund eServices website (eServices using .Net)
- Alrajhi Takaful Internet website (eServices using .Net)
- Council of Saudi Chambers Internet website: SharePoint 2010
- High Commission for the Development of Arrivadh website: SharePoint 2010

## **ERP**

RDCCI ERP web application (using asp.net web forms)

#### **INTRANET PROJECTS**

- Sanabil Intranet : SharePoint 2016 / CMS
- SASO Intranet: SharePoint 2010 / .Net / AngularJs / K2

Page | 2 Muhammad Abusaa

• Ecra intranet : SharePoint 2013 / Word Automation

• GMCO intranet : SharePoint 2013 / CMS

• COE enterprise content management system : SharePoint

AlSubaie intranet : SharePoint 2010

• Riyadh Chamber of Commerce Intranet : SharePoint 2010

#### **EDUCATION**

#### BACHELOR IN COMPUTER SCIENCE, UNIVERSITY OF JORDAN, AMMAN

2005-2009

#### **CERTIFICATIONS**

Designing and Implementing Microsoft DevOps Solutions

Administering Visual Studio Team Foundation Server

Managing Office 365 Identities and Requirements

Developing Microsoft SharePoint Server 2013 Advanced Solutions

Developing Microsoft SharePoint Server 2013 Core Solutions

Advanced Solutions of Microsoft SharePoint Server 2013













Page | 3 Muhammad Abusaa